CHAPTER 9. The Mock Turtles Story “You can’t think how glad I am to see you
again, you dear old thing!” said the Duchess, as she tucked her arm
affectionately into Alice’s, and they walked off together. Alice was very glad
to find her in such a pleasant temper, and thought to herself that perhaps it
was only the pepper that had made her so savage when they met in the kitchen.
“When I’m a Duchess,” she said to herself, (not in a very hopeful tone though), “I
won’t have any pepper in my kitchen at all Soup does very well without—
—Maybe it’s always pepper that makes people hot tempered she went on, very
much pleased at having found out a new kind of rule, “and vinegar that makes them
sour— —and chamomile that makes them bitter— —and— —and barley sugar and such
things that make children sweet tempered I only wish people knew that that they
wouldn’t be so stingy about it, you know—” She had quite forgotten the Duchess by
this time, and was a little startled when she heard her voice close to her ear.
“You’re thinking about something, my dear, and that makes you forget to talk.
I can’t tell you just now what the moral
of that is, but I shall remember it in a bit.” “Perhaps it hasn’t won Alice ventured
to remark. “Tut, tut, child!” said the Duchess. “Everything’s got a
moral, if only you can find it.” And she squeezed herself up closer to Alice’s
side as she spoke.
Alice did not much like keeping so close to her: first, because the Duchess was
very ugly; and secondly, because she was exactly the right height to rest her
chin upon Alice’s shoulder, and it was an uncomfortably sharp chin.
However, she did not like to be rude, so she bore it as well as she could. “The
games going on rather better now,” she said, by way of keeping up the
conversation a little tiso said the Duchess: “and the moral of that is
owed his love his love, that makes the world go round!’”
“Somebody said,” Alice whispered, “that it’s done by everybody minding their own business!”
“Ah, well that means much the same thing,” said the Duchess, digging her sharp
little chin into Alice’s shoulder as she added, “and the moral of that is—‘ —‘Take care
of the sense, and the sounds will take care of themselves.’”
“How fun she is of finding morals and things!” Alice thought to herself.
“I dare say you’re wondering why I don’t put my arm around your waist,” the Duchess
said after a pause: “the reason is, that I’m doubtful about the temper of your
flamingo. Shall I try the experiment?” “He might bite,” Alice cautiously replied,
not feeling at all anxious to have the experiment tried.
“Very true,” said the Duchess flamingos and mustard both bite. And the moral of that
is—‘ —‘Birds of a feather flock together.’” “Only mustard isn’t a bird,” Alice remarked.
“Right, as usual,” said the Duchess: “what a clever way you have of putting things!”
“It’s a mineral, I think said Alice. “Of course it is,” said the Duchess, who seemed
ready to agree to everything that Alice said; “there’s a large mustard mine near
here. And the moral of that is—‘ —‘The more there is of mine, the less there is of
yours.’” “Oh, I know!” exclaimed Alice, who had not attended to
this last remark, “it’s a vegetable. It doesn’t look like one, but it is.”
“I quite agree with you,” said the Duchess; “and the moral of that is—‘ —‘Be what you
would seem to be’— ’—or if you’d like to put it more simply—‘
—‘Never imagine yourself not to be otherwise then white it might appear to
others that you were or might have been was not otherwise than what you have
been would have appeared to them to be otherwise.’” “I think I should understand that better,”
Alice said very politely, “if I had written it down: but I can’t quite follow
it as you say it.” “That’s nothing to what I could say if I
choose the Duchess replied, in a pleased tone.
“Pray don’t trouble yourself to say it any longer than that,” said Alice.
“Oh, don’t talk about trouble!” said the Duchess. “I make you a present of
everything I’ve said as yet.” “A cheap sort of present!” thought Alice.
“I’m glad they don’t give birthday presents like that!” But she did not
venture to say it out loud.
“Thinking again?” the Duchess asked, with another dig of her sharp little chin
I have a right to think,” said Alice sharply, for she was beginning to feel a little worried.
“Just about as much right,” said the Duchess, “as pigs have to fly; and the mo
But here, to Alice’s great surprise, the Duchess’s voice died away, even in the
middle of her favorite word ‘moral,’ and the arm that was linked into hers began to tremble.
Alice looked up, and there stood the Queen in front of them, with her arms
folded, frowning like a thunderstorm.
“A fine day, your Majesty!” the Duchess began in a low, weak voice. “Now, I gave you
fair warning,” shouted the Queen, stamping on the ground as she spoke; “either you or
your head must be off, and that in about half no time! Take your choice!”
The Duchess took her choice, and was gone in a moment.
“Let’s get on with the game,” the Queen said to Alice;
and Alice was too much frightened to say a word, but slowly followed her back to the
croquet ground The other guests had taken advantage of the Queen’s absence, and were resting in
the shade: however, the moment they saw her, they hurried back to the game,
the Queen merely remarking that a moment’s delay would cost them their lives.
All the time they were playing the Queen never left off quarreling with the other
players, and shouting “Off with his head!” or “Off with her head!” Those whom she
sentenced were taken into custody by the soldiers, who of course had to leave off
being arches to do this, so at the end of a half an hour or so
there were no arches left, and all the players, except the King, the Queen, and
Alice, were in custody and under sentence of execution.
Then the Queen left off, quite out of breath, and said to Alice,
“Have you seen the Mock Turtle yet?” “No,” said Alice.
“I don’t even know what a Mock Turtle is.”
“It’s the thing Mock Turtle Soup is made from,” said the Queen. “I never saw one, or
heard of one,” said Alice. “Come on, then,” said the Queen, “and he shall tell you his history.”
As they walked off together, Alice heard the King say in a low voice, to the company generally,
“You are all pardoned.” “Come, that’s a good thing!” she said to
herself, for she had felt quite unhappy at the number of executions the Queen had ordered.
They very soon came upon a griffin lying fast asleep in the sun.
(If you don’t know what a griffin is, look at the picture.)
“Up, lazy thing!” said the Queen, “and take this young lady
to see the Mock Turtle, and to hear his history.
I must go back and see after some executions I have ordered;”
and she walked off, leaving Alice alone with the Griffin
Alice did not quite like the look of the creature, but on the whole she thought it
would be quite as safe to stay with it as to go after that savage Queen:
so she waited.
The Griffin sat up and rubbed its eyes: then it watched the Queen till she was
out of sight: then it chuckled.
“What fun!” said the Griffin half to itself, half to Alice.
“What is the fun?” said Alice. “Why, she said the Griffin
oh It’s all her fancy, that: they never executes nobody, you know.
Come on!” “Everybody says ‘come on!’ here,” thought Alice, as she went slowly after it: “I
never was so ordered about in all my life, never!” They had not gotten very far before they
saw the Mock Turtle in the distance, sitting sad and lonely on a little ledge
of rock, and, as they came nearer, Alice could hear him sighing as if his heart would break.
She pitied him deeply.
“What is his sorrow?” she asked the Griffin and the Griffin answered, very nearly in
the same words as before, “It’s all his fancy, that:
he hasn’t gotten her sorrow, you know.
Come on!” So they went up to the Mock Turtle, who looked at them with large eyes full
of tears, but said nothing.
“This here young lady,” said the Griffin she once forward to know your history, she do.”
“I’ll tell her,” said the Mock Turtle in a deep, hollow tone:
“sit down, both of you, and don’t speak a word till I’ve finished.”
So they sat down, and nobody spoke for some minutes.
Alice thought to herself, “I don’t see how he can even finish, if he doesn’t begin.”
But she waited patiently.
“Once,” said the Mock Turtle at last, with a deep sigh, “I was a real Turtle.”
These words were followed by a very long silence, broken only by an occasional exclamation of
from the Griffin and the constant heavy sobbing of the Mock Turtle.
Alice was very neatly getting up and saying, “Thank you, sir, for your interesting story,”
but she could not help thinking there must be more to come,
so she sat still and said nothing.
“When we were little,” the Mock Turtle went on at last, more calmly, though still
sobbing a little now and then, “we went to school in the sea. The master
was an old title we used to call him Taurus Why did you call him Tortoise, if he
wasn’t one?” Alice asked.
“We called him Tortoise because he taught us,” said the Mock Turtle angrily: “really you
are very dull!” “You ought to be ashamed of yourself for asking such a simple question,”
added the Griffin and then they both sat silent and looked at poor Alice, who felt
ready to sink into the earth.
At last the Griffin said the Mock Turtle, “Drive on, old fellow! Don’t be all day
about it!” and he went on in these words: “Yes, we went to school in the sea, though
you may not believe it—” “I never said I didn’t!” interrupted Alice. “You did,” said
the Mock Turtle. “Hold your tongue!” added the Griffin before Alice could speak
again. The Mock Turtle went on.
“We had the best of educations— —in fact, we
went to school every day—” I’ve been to a
day school too,” said Alice; “you needn’t be so proud as all that.” “With extras?” asked
the Mock Turtle a little anxiously. “Yes,” said Alice, “we learned French and music.”
“And washing?” said the Mock Turtle.
“Certainly not!” said Alice indignantly. “Ah!
then yours wasn’t a really good school,” said the Mock Turtle in a tone of great
relief. “Now at ours they had at the end of the bill, ‘French, music, and washing
—extra.’” “You couldn’t have wanted it much,” said Alice; “living at the bottom of the
sea.” “I couldn’t afford to learn it.” said the Mock Turtle with a sigh. “I only took
the regular course.” “What was that inquire Dallas Reeling and Writhing, of course, to begin
with,” the Mock Turtle replied; “and then the different branches of Arithmetic—
—Ambition, Distraction, Uglification, and Derision.” “I never heard of ‘Uglification,’” Alice
ventured to say. “What is it?” The Griffin lifted up both its paws in
surprise. “What! Never heard of uglifying!” it exclaimed. “You know what to beautify
is, I suppose?” “Yes,” said Alice doubtfully: “it means— —to— —make— —anything— —prettier.”
“Well, then,” the Griffin went on, “if you don’t know
what to uglify is, you are a simpleton.” Alice did not feel encouraged to ask any
more questions about it, so she turned to the Mock Turtle, and said “What else had
you to learn?” “Well, there was Mystery,” the Mock Turtle
replied, counting off the subjects on his flappers, “—Mystery, ancient and modern, with
seography then Drawling— —the drawling master was an old Conga reel that used
to come once a week: he taught us drawing Stretching, and Fainting in Coils.”
“What was that like?” said Alice.
“Well, I can’t show it to you myself,” the
Mock Turtle said: “I’m too stiff. And the Griffin never learned it.” “Hadn’t time,”
said the Griffin I went to the Classics master, though. He was an old crab, he was.”
“I never went to him,” the Mock Turtle said with a sigh: “he taught us Laughing in
Grief, they used to say.” “So he did, so he did,” said the Griffin
sighing in his turn; and both creatures hid their faces in their paws.
“And how many hours a day did you do lessons?” said Alice, in a hurry to change
the subject 10 hours the first day,” said the Mock Turtle: “nine the next, and so on.”
“What a curious plan!” exclaimed Alice.
“That’s the reason they’re called lessons,” the Griffin remarked: “because a lesson
from day to day.” This was quite a new idea to Alice, and
she thought it over a little before she made her next remark.
“Then the 11th day must have been a holiday?” “Of course it was,” said the Mock Turtle.
“And how did you manage on the 12th Alice went on eagerly. “That’s enough about lessons,”
the Griffin interrupted in a very decided tone: “tell her something about the games now